<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./callworkflow.png" type="Other" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Call Remote Workflow (Row Based)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Calls other remote workflows on a KNIME server.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node can be used to call other workflows that reside on a KNIME Server. Input data can be passed to
        Quickform Input nodes (only the new input nodes, e.g <i>Container Input (JSON)</i>) in the other workflow and results can likewise be read back as
        a JSON value from JSON Output nodes(e.g <i>Container Output (JSON)</i>).
        The input can either be a static JSON values provided via the dialog (which itself can be overridden by a flow
        variable) or from a JSON column in the input table. The node will call the other workflow with every row
        of the input table and append the results of the call to it.<br />
        The node will call the other workflow with every row of the input table and append the results of the call to it.
        The same remote workflow can be called by multiple nodes at the same time, a new job is created on the server
        for each node.  
        </intro>

        <tab name="Workflow">

            <option name="Server address">The address to the KNIME Server's REST interface. This is usually something like
                <tt>http://server:8080/knime/rest</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="User">The username on the server.</option>
            <option name="Password">The user's password the server.</option>

            <option name="Short duration: the workflow is expected to run quickly, less than 10 seconds
        				(only applies if the called workflow is executed on a KNIME server)">
                Choose this if the called workflow is expected to finish within ten seconds. When selected, the invocation
                of the workflow will not poll its status, but wait until the job completes (or fails). This removes the
                polling overhead and makes this option quicker for short running workflows. Choosing this option
                for long running workflows (&gt; a minute) will cause timeout problems.
            </option>

            <option name="Long duration: the workflow is expected to run longer than 10 seconds
        				(only applies if the called workflow is executed on a KNIME server)">
                Choose this if the called workflow is expected to run for more than ten seconds. When selected, the
                invocation of the workflow will poll its status, that is start, poll, poll, ..., finish, until the job
                completes (or fails). This option is reasonable for long running workflows where the overhead of regularly
                polling the status is negligible. The polling is implemented so that for the first few seconds there will
                be frequent status checks (poll interval 100ms or 500ms), whereas jobs that run minutes or hours will be
                checked only every few seconds.
            </option>

            <option name="Asynchronous Invocation">The user's password the server.</option>
            <option name="Workflow path">The path of the workflow on the server you want to call. The path must an absolute
                path in the server's repository. You can either enter the path by hand, or click on <i>List available
                    workflows</i> and then select a workflow in the dropdown list.
            </option>
            <option name="Create Report">If checked the report associated with the remote workflow will be generated and
                put into the output table. The format can be chosen in the drop-down. The output table will contain a column
                containing the binary content of the report (column type: binary object); the column can be further processed,
                e.g. use a &quot;Binary Objects to Files&quot; node to write the content to a file, or use a database writer
                to write the report as BLOB into a database. Failures to generate the report
                (for instance, because no report is attached to the workflow) will result in a missing cell.
            </option>
            <option name="Use Fully Qualified Name for Input and Output Parameters">If checked, use the full parameter name
                to select the input and output. The parameter names are
                defined by the user in the configuration dialog
                of each of the parameters (like JSON In/Output node), e.g. "timeout",
                "count", etc. Using these 'simple names'
                may lead to duplicates, hence a 'fully qualified name' is constructed by
                appending a suffix, e.g. "timeout-1" or "count-5:6".
                While these suffixes guarantee unique parameter names across one workflow they may cause
                names not to match in case you
                call out to different workflows (e.g. in a loop). It's good practice to (manually) ensure that parameter
                names in the called workflow are unique and hence often the 'simple name' is sufficient (= do not check the box).
            </option>
            <option name="Inputs">After you have loaded the input format you will see an input block for every input node in
                the called workflow. You can select if you want to use a static value or the value of a column for the respective
                input field or use the default value (that is the value that is set up in the workflow being called).
            </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Advanced Settings">
            <option name="Workflow load timeout">The timeout to use when loading the workflow on the server. Specified
                in seconds. A value of 0 means that no timeout will be used.</option>
            <option name="Server connection timeout">The maximum amount of time to wait when establishing a connection
                to the server. Specified in seconds. A value of 0 means that no timeout will be used.
            </option>
            <option name="Server read timeout">The maximum amount of time to wait when waiting for a response from the
                server. This applies to requests made after the workflow job has been loaded. Specified in seconds.
                A value of 0 means that no timeout will be used.
            </option>
            <option name="Job Status Polling">
                During asynchronous invocation (option "Long Duration"), if a HTTP 5XX error occurs when polling for the
                job status, the node will retry the request. The node will wait a certain amount of time before each retry.
                The time to wait before the <i>n</i>-th attempt is determined by <i>base * multiplier^n</i>.
                Use a multiplier of 1 for a linear, or greater than 1 for an exponential backoff.
                Set the number of retries to 0 to disable retrying.
            </option>
        </tab>

    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input">Any input, possibly with JSON column.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Output">Output of workflow call</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
